jobstreet.com 2013-10-30

# JobStreet.com - Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy

Effective Date: October 11, 2013 

Your privacy is important to JobStreet.com. Please read this Privacy Notice carefully as it forms part of the Terms of Use which govern the use of the JobStreet.com Services and the JobStreet.com Websites. 

JobStreet.com has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site, [http://www.jobstreet.com](http://www.jobstreet.com/ "JobStreet.com - Jobs for Singapore, Malaysia, Philippines, Indonesia, Thailand, Vietnam"). 

TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy Trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us [here](http://myjobstreet.jobstreet.com.my/home/feedback.php?site=my&sub=policy). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact TRUSTe [here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request). 

This Privacy Notice explains:- 

1\. The type of personal information about You which is processed by JobStreet.com when you use the JobStreet.com Services and/or the JobStreet.com Websites; 

2\. How JobStreet.com processes the personal information about You when You use the JobStreet.com Services and the JobStreet.com Websites; 

3\. How JobStreet.com processes the personal information about You when You use the JobStreet.com Services and the JobStreet.com Websites; 

4\. Your right to access and correct Your personal information; 

5\. The class of third parties to which JobStreet.com may disclose Your personal information to; 

6\. Whether it is obligatory or voluntarily for You to supply the personal information and the consequences of failing to provide Your personal information when it is obligatory; and 

7\. How JobStreet.com safeguards the confidentiality and security of Your personal information. 

Any changes will be notified to You via the e-mail address provided by You on registration or via a suitable announcement on the JobStreet.com Websites. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. The changes will apply to the use of the JobStreet.com Services and the JobStreet.com Websites after JobStreet.com have given You notice. If you do not wish to accept the new Terms You should not continue to use the JobStreet.com Services and/or the JobStreet.com Websites. If You continue to use the JobStreet.com Services and/or the JobStreet.com Websites after the date on which the changes comes into effect, Your use of the JobStreet.com Services and/or the JobStreet.com Websites indicates Your agreement to be bound by the new Terms. 

In this Privacy Notice:- 

**“JobStreet.com”, “JobStreet.com Services”, “JobStreet.com Websites”, “You”, “Advertisers”** and **“Employers”** shall have the same meaning as defined in the Terms of Use. 

**“personal information”** is data that can be used to identify an individual. 

**“processing”** includes but is not limited to collecting, holding, storing, recording, organizing, adapting, using, disclosing, correcting, destructing. 

1\. **_COLLECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION_**

1.1 When You register for the JobStreet.com Services 

   | (a)  | Each time when You register with JobStreet.com for any of the JobStreet.com Services, You will be asked to provide certain personal information about Yourself in order to create a MyJobStreet.com account.  
---|---|---  
   | (b)  | The personal information collected during the registration process includes but is not limited to Your email address, name, nationality, identity card number, passport number, country of residence.  
   | (c)  | Whenever the personal information requested by JobStreet.com is marked as “Required Field”, You must provide and agree to the processing of this personal information by JobStreet.com. If You do not agree to provide this personal information and/or not agree to us processing it in the manner set out in this Privacy Notice, then JobStreet.com will be unable to provide the relevant services to You and Your application for such services will be rejected.  
  
1.2 From Your use of the JobStreet.com Services and/or the JobStreet.com Websites 

   | (a)  | We collect personal information directly from You when You choose to engage any of the JobStreet.com Services and/or to use the JobStreet.com Websites. The following are examples of personal information JobStreet.com may collect directly from You:-  | (i)  | Age;  
---|---  
(ii)  | Date of birth;  
(iii)  | telephone number or mobile number;  
(iv)  | Your image;  
(v)  | Academic qualifications;  
(vi)  | Identification documents given by the school/college/university/institute;  
(vii)  | Resumé;  
(viii)  | Personal interests and preferences;  
(ix)  | Working experience;  
(x)  | Credit card or debit card details;  
(xi)  | Other information associated with a resumé for job applications  
   | (b)  | If You choose to add references to Your resumé, JobStreet.com will ask You for their names, telephone numbers, emails, position titles and other relevant particulars. This information will be enclosed as part of your job application and employers may contact them to get references for your applications.  
   | (c)  | If You choose to use JobStreet.com Services to tell a friend about its services or JobStreet.com Websites, JobStreet.com will ask for Your friend’s name and e-mail address. An e-mail inviting Your friend to use the JobStreet.com Services or to visit the JobStreet.com Websites will be sent to him/her automatically.  
   | (d)  | We also collect personal information about You from sources such as Employers, Your referees, and Your school/college/university/institute/professional qualifying bodies.  
   | (e)  | If You wish to stop JobStreet.com from processing this type of personal information about You, JobStreet.com will no longer be able to provide the relevant services to You.  
   | (f)  | (f) In addition, JobStreet.com may ask Your permission to post Your testimonial or success story. If You agree to post Your material on JobStreet.com Websites, You should be aware that any personal information You submit can be read, collected, or used by other users of the JobStreet.com Websites and could be used to send You unsolicited messages. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us [here](http://myjobstreet.jobstreet.com.my/home/feedback.php?site=my&sub=policy).  
  
1.3 When You visit the JobStreet.com Websites 

   | (a)  | When you visit any JobStreet.com Websites our web servers automatically collect information about Your visit to these websites, including Your Internet Protocol (IP) address, the time, date and duration of Your visit. Your IP address is an unique identifier for Your computer or other access device.  
---|---|---  
   | (b)  | JobStreet.com may track Your visits to any JobStreet.com Websites by placing a “cookie” on Your computer or other access device when you enter. Cookies are small text files that are placed on Your computer or other access device by websites that You visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more effectively, as well as to provide information to the owners of the websites.  
   | (c)  | Cookies allow JobStreet.com to save preferences for You so that you will not have to re-enter them the next time You visit. Cookies also help JobStreet.com collect anonymous click stream data for tracking user trends and patterns. JobStreet.com may use the anonymous click stream data to help the Advertiser to deliver better-targeted advertisements. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.  
   | (d)  | You can remove cookies by following directions provided in your internet browser’s “help” file. You should understand that areas of certain websites will not function properly if You set Your internet browser to not accept cookies.  
   | (e)  | JobStreet.com also uses clear gifs in its HTML-based emails in order to find out which emails have been opened by the recipients. This allows JobStreet.com to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of its marketing campaigns.  
   | (f)  | Our partners and service providers use cookies to collect information about the usage of JobStreet.com websites. The use of cookies by our partners and service providers is not covered by our privacy policy. We do not have access or control over these cookies.  
   | ()  |   
  
2\. **_PURPOSES OF COLLECTING AND USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION_**

2.1 The purposes for which JobStreet.com processes Your personal information are as follows:- 

   | (a)  | To verify Your identity;  
---|---|---  
   | (b)  | To assess and/or verify Your employability and credit worthiness;  
   | (c)  | To provide the JobStreet.com Services which You have requested;  
   | (d)  | To administer and manage the JobStreet.com Services provided to You;  
   | (e)  | To contact You in respect of JobStreet.com Services;  
   | (f)  | To verify Your academic and professional qualification by contacting the school/college/university/institute/professional qualifying bodies;  
   | (g)  | To contact the referee and/or the guarantor whom details have been provided by You;  
   | (h)  | To process Your order for the JobStreet.com Services which You have requested;  
   | (i)  | To investigate and resolve any of the JobStreet.com Services, billing queries, complaints or other enquiries that You submit to JobStreet.com regarding JobStreet.com Services;  
   | (j)  | To manage staff training and quality assurance;  
   | (k)  | To monitor and improve the performance of the JobStreet.com Websites and the JobStreet.com Services;  
   | (l)  | To maintain and develop the JobStreet.com Websites and JobStreet.com Services;  
   | (m)  | To gain an understanding of Your information and communication needs in order for JobStreet.com to enhance and customize the JobStreet.com Services;  
   | (n)  | To conduct research and development and statistical analysis in connection with the JobStreet.com Services to identify trends and develop new services that reflect Your interests;  
   | (o)  | To assist JobStreet.com in understanding Your browsing preferences on the JobStreet.com Websites so that JobStreet.com can tailor content accordingly;   
   | (p)  | To detect and prevent fraudulent activity.  
  
2.2 You are not able to limit the processing of Your personal information for the purposes set out in Clause 2.1 above. If You do not consent to JobStreet.com processing Your personal information for the said purposes, You must terminate Your relevant agreement with JobStreet.com for the JobStreet.com Services and stop using the JobStreet.com Websites. 

2.3 JobStreet.com will ask for Your consent before processing Your personal information other than those set out in Clause 2.1. 

2.4 In addition, JobStreet.com may use Your personal information for the following purposes:- 

   | (a)  | To promote and market to You:  
(i) Other JobStreet.com Services; or  
(ii) Services of third parties which JobStreet.com thinks may be of interest of You; and   
---|---|---  
   | (b)  | To send You seasonal greeting messages and/or message informing You of a critical performance error in the JobStreet.com Websites and/or the JobStreet.com Services.  
   | (c)  | To send You tips, advice and survey information to maximize Your career development including but not limited to using the JobStreet.com Services and/or the JobStreet.com Websites.  
  
3\. **_RESUME_**

3.1 JobStreet.com gives You the option of putting Your resumé in the JobStreet.com Resumé Database provided that You use JobStreet.com’s preset format for uploading Your resumé. There are two ways of doing so:- 

   | (a)  | You can store your resumé in the JobStreet.com Resumé Database, but not allow it to be searchable by potential Employers or Advertisers or SiVa Account Holders. Not allowing Your resumé to be searchable means that You can use it to apply for a job online, but Employers or Advertisers or SiVa Account Holders will not have access to search it through the JobStreet.com Resumé Database.  
---|---|---  
   | (b)  | You can allow Your resumé to be searchable by Employers or Advertisers or SiVa Account Holders. When You opt to make Your resumé searchable, you still have the choice to make Your personal information confidential where all of Your contact information can remain hidden. This information will be hidden if You have enter them accordingly into the given form. However, information entered into other fields such as working experience will remain viewable to the Employers or Advertisers or SiVa Account Holders under this option.  
  
3.2 JobStreet.com uses its best effort to restrict access to the JobStreet.com Resumé Database only to those who have subscribed to the JobStreet.com Services, these parties may retain a copy of Your resumé in their own files or databases. 

3.3 JobStreet.com will take reasonable steps to ensure that parties other than those mentioned above will not, without JobStreet.com’s consent, gain access to the JobStreet.com Resumé Database. However, JobStreet.com is not responsible for the retention, use or privacy of resumé by any third parties. 

4\. **_CHOICE AND ACCESS OF PERSONAL INFORMATION_**

4.1 You may have different privacy concerns. JobStreet.com’s goal is to be clear of what information it collects, so that You can make meaningful choices about how it is used. For example:- 

   | (a)  | You can control who you share Your personal information with;  
---|---|---  
   | (b)  | You can review and control Your subscription to various marketing preferences, JobStreet.com Services;  
   | (c)  | You may view, edit or delete Your personal information and preferences at any time.  
   | (d)  | You may choose not to receive any marketing materials from JobStreet.com;  
   | (e)  | You may also subscribe to additional JobStreet.com Services;  
   | by logging into a MyJobStreet.com account.  
  
4.2 You can delete Your MyJobStreet.com account at any time in which event JobStreet.com will remove all access to Your account and resume in the database. The deletion of Your MyJobStreet.com account does not affect resumés that You had already sent to Employers or were previously downloaded by Employers, Advertisers or SiVa Account Holders. 

5\. **_RETENTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION_**

5.1 JobStreet.com will retain Your personal information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes set out in Clause 2 above and any legal or business purposes. 

6\. **_SECURITY OF PERSONAL INFORMATION_**   
6.1 JobStreet.com is committed to keeping personal information secure. JobStreet.com has appropriate technical, administrative and physical procedures in place to protect personal information from loss, theft and misuse, as well as against unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. Sensitive information (such as a credit card number) entered on our payment gateway services are encrypted during the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). 

6.2 No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us [here](http://myjobstreet.jobstreet.com.my/home/feedback.php?site=my&sub=policy). 

7\. **_TO WHOM PERSONAL INFORMATION IS DISCLOSED_**

7.1 Personal information mentioned in Clause 1 above may be disclosed to the classes of third parties as follows in order for JobStreet.com to effectively manage its business including to render the JobStreet.com Services to You to achieve the purposes described in Clause 2:- 

   | (a)  | The Advertisers;  
---|---|---  
   | (b)  | The Employers;  
   | (c)  | Third parties contracted by JobStreet.com to assist JobStreet.com in delivering all or part of the JobStreet.com Services to You, including without limitation, to the following:-   
(i) Payment gateway services for optional services;  
(ii) Profiling/assessment services;  
(iii) Online advertising services;  
(iv) Mapping services;  
(v) Maintenance and repair services; and  
(vi) Market research and website usage analysis services.  
  
   | (d)  | Strategic partners that work with JobStreet.com to provide the JobStreet.com Services or that help market and promote JobStreet.com Services and/or JobStreet.com Websites;  
   | (e)  | The school/college/university/institute You studied at and Your referees so as to verify your academic qualification;  
   | (f)  | Professional qualifying bodies where You obtained Your accreditation;  
   | (g)  | Regulatory bodies, governmental bodies or other authorities if required or authorized to do so to discharge any regulatory function, under any law or in relation to any order or judgment of a court;  
   | (h)  | Regulatory bodies, governmental bodies or other authorities for the purpose of detection or prevention of crime, illegal/unlawful activities or fraud or for the apprehension or prosecution of offenders, or for an investigation relating to any of these;  
   | (i)  | Any party involved in or related to a legal proceeding (or prospective legal proceeding), for purposes of the legal proceedings;  
   | (j)  | JobStreet.com’s professional advisors on a need to know basis for the purpose of those advisors providing advice to JobStreet.com;  
   | (k)  | Any third party which acquires all or part of the assets or business of JobStreet.com (including accounts and trade receivables) for the purpose of that third party continuing to provide all or that part of the JobStreet.com Services which it acquired; and  
   | (l)  | Otherwise permitted under any data protection legislation.  
  
7.2 Other than set out above, You will receive notice when personal information about You might go to third parties, and You will have an opportunity to choose not to share the information. 

7.3 JobStreet.com does not sell or rent any personal information collected to any other parties. 

8\. **_YOUR OBLIGATIONS REGARDING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION_**

8.1 You are responsible for providing accurate, not misleading, complete and up-to-date information to JobStreet.com about Yourself and any other person whose personal information You provide us and for updating this personal information as and when it becomes inaccurate, misleading, incomplete and out-of-date by contacting JobStreet.com [here](http://myjobstreet.jobstreet.com.my/home/feedback.php?site=my&sub=policy). 

8.2 In the circumstances you may need to provide to JobStreet.com personal information about someone other than Yourself (for example, Your referee or guarantor). If so, we rely on You to inform these individual that You are providing their personal information to JobStreet.com, to make sure they consent to You giving us their information and to advise them about where they can find a copy of this Privacy Notice (on our website at [Privacy Policy](http://www.jobstreet.com.my/aboutus/privacy_policy.htm)]) 

9\. **_TRANSFER OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION OUTSIDE OF YOUR LOCAL JURISDICTION_**

9.1 It may be necessary for JobStreet.com to transfer Your personal information outside of your local jurisdiction if any of JobStreet.com’s service providers or strategic partners (“overseas entities”) are involved in providing part of the JobStreet.com Services. 

10\. **_LINKED SITES_**

10.1 JobStreet.com Websites that may contain links to third party sites. 

10.2 JobStreet.com is not responsible for such third party sites. Any personal information made available by You on such sites will not have the benefit of this Privacy Notice and will be subject to the relevant third party’s privacy policy (if any). 

10.3 You can login to our site using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect. This service will authenticate Your identity and provide You the option to share certain personal information with us such as Your name and email address to pre-populate our sigh-up form. Services like Facebook Connect give You the option to post information about Your activities on this website to Your profile page to share with others within Your network. 

10.4 Our website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook button and widgets, or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These features may collect You IP address, which page that You are visiting on our site, and may set a cookies to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and widgets are either hosted by third party or hosted directly on our site. Your interaction with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

11\. **_YOUR CONSENT_**

11.1 In using the JobStreet.com Services and/or the JobStreet.com Websites, You consent to the collections and use of the personal information by JobStreet.com in the ways described hereinabove (which may change from time to time) unless and until You inform JobStreet.com to the contrary [here](http://myjobstreet.jobstreet.com.my/home/feedback.php?site=my&sub=policy). 

11.2 Further, You consent to Your referees, the school/college/university/institute where You have studied, the professional qualifying bodies where You received Your accreditation and Employers to disclose Your personal information to JobStreet.com. 

12\. **_CONTACT INFORMATION_**

12.1 If you still have questions about this Privacy Notice, please visit Help or Frequently Asked Questions on the JobStreet.com Websites. JobStreet.com requests Your name, phone number, email address and comments so that JobStreet.com may respond to Your concerns effectively and work to improve the JobStreet.com Services and/or JobStreet.com Websites. 

JobStreet Corporation Berhad  
Wisma JobStreet.com  
No. 27, Lorong Medan Tuanku 1  
(Off Jalan Sultan Ismail)  
50300 Kuala Lumpur.
